Guide to the Brooklyn, N.Y., Department of Law, Corporation Counsel records 2013.015
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Case Files, 1849-1920; 98.0 linear feet; in 199 manuscripts boxes, 4 flat boxes and 1 flat file drawer
  - Kings County Court assistant clerk salaries, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Kipp, John - Board of Commissioners of Charities and Corrections services, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Kirwin, James, as Administrator of John Kirwin - Meeker Ave. Newtown Creek bridge death, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Klein, Kate - 63 Ryerson St. injury, 1896-1897 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Kleine, Virginia A. - Tax sale surplus, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    Ward 25 - Block 147 - Lots 2-3 (Broadway, between McDonough St. and Decatur St.)
  - Koester, Christian - Butler St. and Washington Ave. foreclosure, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    This section of Butler St. is now known as Sterling Pl.
  - Lachman, Louis S. - Petit larceny, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Lauritz, Peter J. and Charles L. Perry - County Farm plans and specifications dispute, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Lee, Hop - Coney Island Iron Pier fire property damage, 1896 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Lenhart, P. Frederick - 575 and 578 Greene Ave. sewer property damage, 1896-1897 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Liquor license rebates (1 of 5), 1896 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    George C. Butcher, Louis Detweiler, Eastern Brewing Company (Abbot-Katz Brewing Company), F. and M. Schaefer Brewing Company, Maurice A Kraus, Leibinger and Oehm Brewing Company, Peter McCormick, Henry Miller, Henry F. Nieber, John H. Puckhaber, Gabriel Sontheimer, Leo Stein, William Ulmer, V. Savarese and Bros., John P. Waldmuller, William H. Frank Brewing Company, and others
  - Liquor license rebates (2 of 5), 1896 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    George C. Butcher, Louis Detweiler, Eastern Brewing Company (Abbot- Katz Brewing Company), F. and M. Schaefer Brewing Company, Maurice A Kraus, Leibinger and Oehm Brewing Company, Peter McCormick, Henry Miller, Henry F. Nieber, John H. Puckhaber, Gabriel Sontheimer, Leo Stein, William Ulmer, V. Savarese and Bros., John P. Waldmuller, William H. Frank Brewing Company, and others
  - Liquor license rebates (3 of 5), 1896 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Liquor license rebates (4 of 5), 1896 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Liquor license rebates (5 of 5), 1896 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Ludden, Adelaide B. - Douglass St., between Plaza St. and Underhill Ave. - Foreclosure (1 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    This section of Douglass St. is now known as St. Johns Pl.; Folder (2 of 2) located in oversized box 237
  - Ludden, Adelaide B. - Douglass St., between Plaza St. and Underhill Ave. - Foreclosure (2 of 2), 1896- 1897 (Box 237, Folder -)
    Foreclosure sale poster; This section of Douglass St. is now known as St. Johns Pl.
  - Malcolm Brewing Company - Assessment dispute (1 of 3), 1896- 1897 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Malcolm Brewing Company - Assessment dispute (2 of 3), 1896- 1897 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Malcolm Brewing Company - Assessment dispute (3 of 3), 1896- 1897 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Malone, Annie M. - Ocean Ave. and Voorhees Ave. rent dispute, 1896 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Mangan, Daniel C. - Expert testimony services, 1896 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Manhattan Savings Institution, 1896 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Markey, Kate, as administratrix of Hugh Markey - Meeker Ave. bridge death, 1896 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Marshall, Chauncey and Martha A., as executors of William Marshall - Assessment dispute, 1896-1898 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Martin, David - Manhattan Ave. fire engine accident, 1896-1897 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - McCarthy, Helen - 897 Halsey St. sewer property damage, 1896-1899 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    Or Ellen
  - McCarty, Patrick - St. Marks Ave. fence damage, 1896 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - McGinniss, John J. - Board of Supervisors employee salary, 1896 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - McGoe, Peter - Assessment dispute, 1896 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    Ward 24 - Block 183 - Lot 48 (Dean St., between Rochester Ave. and Utica Ave.)
  - McGuire, Michael - 185 2nd Ave. property damage, 1896 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - McKeever, Edward J. and Stephen W. - Street cleaning contract dispute (1 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - McKeever, Edward J. and Stephen W. - Street cleaning contract dispute (2 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - McKeever, Stephen W. and Edward J. against William Kelly and George H. Sterling - Paving contract dispute, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - McMahon, Frank against Frederick E. Remsen, et al - Contract dispute, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Milliken, Edward F. and Foster - Sewer construction contract dispute, 1896-1898 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Millikin Brothers
  - Mulligan, Bartlett T. - South 3rd St. wagon property damage, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Mumford, Thaddeous - False arrest, 1896-1897 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Murphy - Civil Justice services, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Murphy, James W. and Michael McCormack - Washington Ave. and St. Marks Ave. tax sale dispute, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    Ward 9 - Block 25 - Lot 1 (Bergen St., between Washington Ave. and Grand Ave.)
  - Murray, Joseph, 1896-1897 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Nassau Electric Railroad Company - Assessment dispute (1 of 2), 1896-1899 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Nassau Electric Railroad Company - Assessment dispute (2 of 2), 1896-1899 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Nassau Electric Railroad Company - Buffalo Ave. track, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Nassau Electric Railroad Company - Soft coal use violation, 1896-1897 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    City of Brooklyn against the Nassau Electric Railroad Company; Engine room and electrical station located at 1st St. and 3rd Ave.
  - New Utrecht Improvement Company - Tax sale dispute, 1896 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - New York and Queens County Railway Company - Long Island City assessment dispute, 1896- 1897 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - New York and Sea Beach Railway Company - 65th St. opening dispute, 1896 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Newman, Richard J. and others - 589 Vanderbilt Ave. foreclosure, 1896-1897 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    Ward 9 - Block 27 - Lot 98
  - Noble, John S. - Radde St. engine house rental, 1896- 1898 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Nuttall, William - Tinsmith dismissal (1 of 2), 1896- 1898 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    Dismissed because his work was to be done by County prisoners
  - Nuttall, William - Tinsmith dismissal (2 of 2), 1896- 1898 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - O'Brien, William J. - 176 Butler St. sewer property damage, 1896- 1899 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - O'Neill, George, 1896 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Orr, Alexander E. and others - Civil Service Commission appropriations, 1896 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Parkhill, Edith H., as assignee of David McKee - Tax sale surplus, 1896 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    Ward 24 - Block 205 - Lots 13-14 (Dean St., between Buffalo Ave. and Ralph Ave.)
  - Partridge, Josiah, et al - Northeast corner of Leonard Ave. and Van Pelt Ave. water damage, 1896-1899 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    Van Pelt Ave. now known as Engert Ave.
  - Patterson, James, as Administrator of Thomas Patterson - Commerce St. death, 1896 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Pattison, Annie L., George H., and others - Foreclosure (1 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    Prospect Pl. and Washington Ave.
  - Pattison, Annie L., George H., and others - Foreclosure (2 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Railroad speed violations (1 of 4), 1896-1897 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Railroad speed violations (2 of 4), 1896-1897 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Railroad speed violations (3 of 4), 1896-1897 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Railroad speed violations (4 of 4), 1896-1897 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Rath, Wilhelmina - Estate of Herman H.W. Moeller dispute, 1896-1897 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    Driggs Ave. and Humboldt St.
  - Reilly, Thomas F. - Fireman salary, 1896-1897 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Resseguie, David M. - 9th Ave. paving contract dispute, 1896 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    This section of 9th Ave. is now known as Prospect Park West
  - Rex, Joseph, 1896 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    State of New York against Rex
  - Rieff, Albert - Ocean Ave. wagon accident, 1896- 1897 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Rugen, Catharine and Lillian Haskell - 23rd St. injuries, 1896- 1901 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Saauze, Marietta - 782a Hancock St. sewer property damage, 1896- 1897 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Saffen, Henry C. - County Clerk, 1896 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Samuels, Esther - Hudson Ave. sidewalk injury, 1896- 1897 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Saunders, William C. against Timothy L. Woodruff, individually and as Commissioner of Parks - Ocean Parkway horse death, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Sbrignadello, John - 1039 Fulton St. public nuisance, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Schenck, Daniel S. against William M. Boyle and Edwin Brown - False imprisonment, 1896-1898 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Schomaker, John - Liquor license dispute, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    2465 Atlantic Ave.
  - Schuster, Moritz - 22 Grand St. sidewalk injury, 1896- 1918 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Schwab, Franz Michael - Murder, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Schwartz, Marcus L. - Railroad worker injury, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Senior, Catherine, as administratrix of Mary McDonough - Park Ave. death, 1896-1899 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Sheridan, Phillip J. and others - Department of City Works dismissals, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Shoen, Herman - Assessment dispute, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Short, Joseph M. - Special inspector of school houses dismissal (1 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Short, Joseph M. - Special inspector of school houses dismissal (2 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Simis, A., Jr. - City building construction dispute, 1896 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    Simis was the President of the Board of Commissioners of Charities and Corrections
  - Smith, Gray and Company - Strike property damage, 1896 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Walter R. - Freeport property damage (1 of 3), 1896-1902 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    Damage caused by Brooklyn water supply aqueducts; Folder (3 of 3) located in oversized box 236
  - Smith, Walter R. - Freeport property damage (2 of 3), 1896-1902 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Walter R. - Freeport property damage (3 of 3), 1896-1902 (Box 236, Folder -)
    Map
  - Smits, Theodore A. - Opening of Broadway to Liberty Ave. dispute, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    Corner of Liberty Ave. and Eldert's Lane
  - Smyth, Julia M. - Assessment dispute, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    Ward 25 (all): Block 60 - Lot 49 (block bound by Chauncey St., Bainbridge St., Ralph Ave., and Howard Ave.); Block 109 - Lots 45, 48, and 64 (Marion St., between Hopkinson Ave. and Rockaway Ave.)
  - Sondern, Emma E., as Committee of the person and estate of Wilhelmina Kunz - Tax sale surplus, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    Ward 24 - Block 236 - Lot 92 (Atlantic Ave., between Rockaway Ave. and Stone Ave.)
  - Stoddard, Lucy E. - Tax sale surplus, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    Ward 24 - Block 130 - Lot 2 (Atlantic Ave., near Albany Ave)
  - Uppington, Mary T. - 770 Greene Ave. sewer property damage (1 of 3), 1896-1899 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    Includes 6 photographs of sewer construction at Greene Ave. and Marcy Ave.
  - Uppington, Mary T. - 770 Greene Ave. sewer property damage (2 of 3), 1896-1899 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Uppington, Mary T. - 770 Greene Ave. sewer property damage (3 of 3), 1896-1899 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Waldmuller, John P., 1896 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Walradt, Arthur E., as assignee of Albert H. Smith, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    Regarding legal fees
  - Walsh, Luke - Brooklyn Bridge cable car injury, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Ware, Alice - Tax sale surplus, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    Ward 11 - Block 133 - Lot 3 (Johnson St., between Bridge St. and Duffield St.)
  - Webner, Mary - Last will and testament of Samuel Frost, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - West, Filey, 1896 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - West, George E. - Assessment dispute, 1896-1897 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    Ward 7 - Block 7 (old block 3) - Lots 51-52 (old lots 49 -50) (Grand Ave., between Flushing Ave. and Park Ave.)
  - White, Alexander P., Clarence B., and Herbert E. - Contract dispute, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    Incandescent Burner Company
  - Williams, William - Hamilton Ave. (near Gowanus bridge) sidewalk injury, 1896-1898 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Woffshlager, Alexander - 159 21st St. fire hydrant injury, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Wolfe, William - Common Show license for carousel, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    Kent Homestead located on block bound by 59th St., 60th St., 2nd Ave., and New York Bay
  - Woodhull, Sells - Pacific St. sleigh injury, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Woodruff, Benjamin N. - Clerk services, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Woodruff, Timothy L. (Brooklyn Commissioner of Parks) against Frank Squier (Kings County Commissioner of Parks) - County parks and roads, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Wright, George S. - 249 Manhattan Ave. property damage, 1896 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, Henry - Kings County Jail repair bills, 1897 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Atkins, Harry S. against John J. Lack - Finolithic Stone Company contract dispute, 1897-1898 (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Barlow, George - 210 Halsey St. sewer property damage, 1897 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Berger, Victoria - 17th Ave., from Cropsey Ave. to Gravesend Bay opening dispute, 1897 (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Bischoff, Henry W. - South 4th St. horse injury, 1897 (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Blackwell, Jennet - Long Island City assessment dispute, 1897 (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Blaschko, Max - East River and Atlantic Ocean Railroad Company injunction, 1897-1898 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    See also Norris, John - East River and Atlantic Ocean Railroad Company and the Nassau Electric Railroad Company injunction, 1897- 1898
  - Booden, Patrick and Elizabeth - Douglass St. and Underhill Ave.; and Washington Ave, between Degraw St. and Eastern Parkway foreclosures, 1897 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    This section of Douglass St. is now known as St. Johns Pl.; this section of Degraw St. is now known as Lincoln Pl.
  - Bradley, William and William B. - contract dispute, 1897 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn and Rockaway Beach Railroad Company - Assessment dispute, 1897 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn City Railroad Company and Brooklyn Heights Railroad Company - Assessment dispute (1 of 4), 1897-1898 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn City Railroad Company and Brooklyn Heights Railroad Company - Assessment dispute (2 of 4), 1897-1898 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn City Railroad Company and Brooklyn Heights Railroad Company - Assessment dispute (3 of 4), 1897-1898 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn City Railroad Company and Brooklyn Heights Railroad Company - Assessment dispute (4 of 4), 1897-1898 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn Elevated Railroad Company - Assessment and taxation, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn Queens County and Suburban Railroad Company - Assessment dispute, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn Queens County and Suburban Railroad Company - Jamaica Plank Rd. dispute, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    Includes drawing of curve and siding at Jamaica Plank Rd. and Crescent St.
  - Brown, Selina L. - 626 Greene Ave. sewer property damage, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Brumley, James L. - Electrification franchise injunction, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Burchard, Florence L. - Tax sale surplus, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    Ward 25 - Block 42 (old block 78) - Lot 52 (Monroe St., between Patchen Ave. and Reid Ave. (now Malcolm X Blvd.))
  - Burger, Anthony J. and George W. Delap - Coroner elections, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    Complaint arising from consolidation of Brooklyn with New York City
  - Burke, James - 3rd Ave. and 47th St. sewer property damage, 1897-1898 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Burns, Julia - 65 Maspeth Ave. property damage, 1897 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Carlin, John C. - 24th Precinct Police Station alterations (1 of 3), 1897-1899 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    Includes specifications; West 8th St., Coney Island; Folder (3 of 3) is located in oversized box 236
  - Carlin, John C. - 24th Precinct Police Station alterations (2 of 3), 1897-1899 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Carlin, John C. - 24th Precinct Police Station alterations (3 of 3), 1897-1899 (Box 236, Folder -)
  - Carlin, P. J., F. W., and John J., 1897 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Carney, Richard M. against the Village of College Point - Improvements contract dispute, 1897-1898 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Carolei, Annie - Brooklyn Bridge injury, 1897-1898 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Carpenter, James O. and Alena F. - Vanderbilt Ave. and Park Pl. foreclosure, 1897 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Casino Land Company - Long Island City assessment dispute, 1897-1898 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Citizens Electric Illuminating Company of Brooklyn, Edison Electric Illuminating Company of Brooklyn, and Municipal Electric Light Company of Brooklyn - Tax dispute (1 of 2), 1897-1898 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    See also Edison Electric Illuminating Company of Brooklyn, 1896 -1898
  - Citizens Electric Illuminating Company of Brooklyn, Edison Electric Illuminating Company of Brooklyn, and Municipal Electric Light Company of Brooklyn - Tax dispute (2 of 2), 1897-1898 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Clarke, Thomas A. - Broadway sidewalk injury, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Cocheu, Fred C. - Sea Beach Railway Company dispute, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    Regarding steam railroad on the same grade as Fort Hamilton Parkway
  - Cohen, Aaron - Stone Ave. horse injury, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    Stone Ave. is now Mother Gaston Blvd.
  - Coney Island Fuel Gas and Light Company, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Cooley, George W. vs. Trustees of New York and Brooklyn Bridge, 1897-1899 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    Includes 1886 agreement between the New Yorker Staats Zeitung and the Manhattan Railway Company and the New York Elevated Railroad Company and the Trustees of the New York and Brooklyn Bridge
  - Crane, Winthrop M. - Long Island City assessment dispute, 1897-1898 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Devau, Martin - Sidewalk injury, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Donohue, Hugh J. - 285 Clinton St. sidewalk injury, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Douglas, LeGrand against the Board of Education - Carpenter dismissal, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Drebinger, Frederica - 41 Starr St. sidewalk injury, 1897 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - Drummond, Michael J. against Long Island City - Water Department supplies compensation, 1897-1899 (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - Duboise, George R. - Court janitor salary, 1897- 1898 (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - Duryea, Louis T. - Flatbush Gas Company gas conduction dispute (1 of 2), 1897 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Duryea, Louis T. - Flatbush Gas Company gas conduction dispute (2 of 2), 1897 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Eckhoff, Meta - President St. and Columbia St. crosswalk injury, 1897 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Excelsior Brewing Company - Assessment dispute (1 of 2), 1897-1899 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    Ward 21 - Block 46 - Lots 105-107 (Pulaski St., between Throop Ave. and Marcus Garvey Blvd.); Also includes Bush Brewing Company, Coney Island Jockey Club, and William Ulmer
  - Excelsior Brewing Company - Assessment dispute (2 of 2), 1897- 1899 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Fahy, James T. vs. Trustees of the Village of Edgewater, 1897 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Farrell, John J. and Thomas Marra - Long Island City engineer salaries, 1897-1899 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Fire Department - Madison St., between Central Ave. and Hamburg Ave. assessment dispute, 1897 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    Ward 28 - Block 52 - Lot 77; Hamburg Ave. is now known as Wilson Ave.
  - Flatbush Gas Company - Assessment dispute (1 of 2), 1897-1898 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Flatbush Gas Company - Assessment dispute (2 of 2), 1897-1898 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Forker and Baldwin against Mary Auguste Titus - Washington St. and Johnson St. foreclosure, 1897 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    This section of Washington St. is now known as Cadman Plaza East
  - Frederickson, Frederick W. and others - Tax sale dispute, 1897 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    Ward 30 - Block 44 - Lots 45-46 (59th St., between 13th Ave. and 14th Ave.)
  - Friberg, Charles A. - Driggs Ave. and North 13th St. sewer property damage, 1897-1900 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Gibbons (?), 1897 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Gleason and Bailey Manufacturing Company, Limited - Long Island City hose wagons sale, 1897-1898 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Gouge, Henry A. - Courthouse ventilation contract dispute, 1897 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    Includes ventilating and heating specifications for Kings County Court House
  - Grady, William - Horse and wagon services, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Greenblatt, Louis - Discharge of debts, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Greenpoint Sporting Club - Public athletic exhibition license, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Gregg, Bridget - Manhattan Ave. crosswalk injury, 1897-1899 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Groton Bridge and Manufacturing Company - Meeker Ave. Newtown Creek bridge construction, 1897-1898 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Hastings, William H. - Long Island City draughtsman salary, 1897- 1898 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Hellwig, Maurice - City Clerk bill, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Hickie, Patrick T. - Hatton Pl. obstructions, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Hill Athletic Club - License for sparring exhibitions, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    Dispute related to boxing matches; 193 Clermont Ave.
  - Hiller, Theodore, Jr. - Spring Creek Pumping Station farm property damage, 1897-1898 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Hoagland Laboratory - Rent claim, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    Corner of Pacific St. and Henry St.
  - Holton, Flora Stearns and Edwin R. Collard - East River and Atlantic Ocean Railroad Company injunction, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Humphreys, George - Coney Island caisson contract dispute, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Inebriates' Home for Kings County - License issue, 1897 (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Janes, Isabella A., as Administratrix of the estate of William H. Janes, against the Village of New Brighton - Fireman death, 1897- 1898 (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Jenkins, John G. and others - Assessment dispute, 1897- 1902 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    Stockholders of the First National Bank of Brooklyn
  - Kelly, Thomas - Assessment dispute, 1897- 1898 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    Ward 3 - Block 24 - Lots 8-11 (Fulton St., between Hoyt St. and Elm Pl.)
  - Kelly, William against James Campbell, John Mara, James Gilchrist, and John McCormick - False arrest, 1897 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Kings County Bank - Assessment dispute, 1897-1898 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    Ward 22
  - Kings County Elevated Railroad Company - Assessment and taxation, 1897 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Kleinfeld, Lillie - Wagon accident injury, 1897 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Koehler, Augustus J. - Property auctioneer's fees, 1897-1898 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    Ward 9 - Block 38 - Lot 32 (Bergen St., between Grand Ave. and Classon Ave.)
  - Koehler, David M. against Richard Cody, James Cody, and William Cody - Creditor-Debtor dispute, 1897 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Kouwenhoven, Francis D. - Long Island City assessment dispute (1 of 2), 1897-1898 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Kouwenhoven, Francis D. - Long Island City assessment dispute (2 of 2), 1897-1898 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Kramer, Andrew and Elizabeth - Tax dispute, 1897 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    Ward 16 - Block 93 - Lot 43 (Varet St. and Humboldt St.)
  - Kraus, Maurice A. - The Ferdinand Munch Brewery - Liquor license dispute, 1897 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    64 Flatbush Ave.
  - Kugel, Adam H. - Marriage certificate correction, 1897 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Kuhn, John - Assessment dispute, 1897 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    Ward 12 - Block 349 - Lot 42 (44 and 46 Elizabeth St. (now Beard St.)
  - Lambertson, Jere - Reid Ave. and Macon St. injury, 1897 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    Reid Ave. now known as Malcolm X Blvd.
  - Lawrence, John L. - Town of Hempstead lighting district dispute, 1897-1898 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    Includes detailed maps. Maps are fragile and should only be handled under supervision of library staff.
  - Lawrence, John W., for damages for loss of services of his son Joseph C. Lawrence - Meeker Ave. bridge death, 1897 (Box 92, Folder 8)